So, for the medical model, it seems that we'd much rather
对于医疗模型 似乎我们宁愿
将健康人士误诊为生病人士 并继续加以检查
misdiagnose a healthy person as sick and send them for more tests,
也不希望将生病人士误诊为健康人士 并让他们直接回家而不接受治疗
than misdiagnose a sick person who's healthy and send them home without treatment.
In this case, a false negative is much worse than a false positive.
在这种情况下假阴性比假阳性更糟糕
这个模型的规则是
So the rule of this model is,
I want to find all the sick people.
我想要找出所有生病的人士
不小心找到了更多的生病人士也没关系
I'm okay if I accidentally bring some more as sick,
but I need to find all the sick people.
我需要找到所有生病的人
对于垃圾邮件
And for the spam email model, let's see.
假阴性是指垃圾邮件进入了收件箱
A false negative means a spam email made its way into your inbox,
你只需将其删掉
and all you have to do is delete it.
因此不太方便
So it's a bit of an inconvenience.
另一方面假阳性是什么情况呢？
On the other hand, what's a false positive?
Your grandma, the poor lady learned to type an email only to tell
可怜的外婆学会了发电子邮件
只为了告诉你她做了一些曲奇 但是你给删了 太可怕了
you she baked cookies and you delete it. That's terrible.
因此我们希望假阳性的惩罚比假阴性的更重
So here, we want to punish false positives more than false negatives.
这个模型的含义是
So this model basically says,
我并不关心是否找到了所有的垃圾邮件
I don't really care if I find all the spam emails,
但有一点值得肯定的是
but one thing is for sure,
如果说某封邮件是垃圾邮件 则最好是垃圾邮件
if I say that an email is spam, it better be spam.
因此 医疗模型和电子邮件模型在本质上是完全不同的
So as we can see, the medical model and the email model are fundamentally different.
The medical model as we saw is okay with false positives,
医疗模型可以接受假阳性
but not with false negatives.
但不能接受假阴性
Since we're okay misdiagnosing some patients
因为我们可以将某人误诊为生病人士
只要找到所有生病人士即可
as sick as long as we find all the sick people.
另一方面
The email model on the other hand,
is okay with false negatives but not with false positives,
邮件模型可以接受假阴性 但不能接受假阳性
因为我们不需要找到所有的垃圾邮件
since we don't necessarily need to find all the spam emails.
但有一定可以肯定的是
But one thing is for sure,
that if we do label something as spam, it better be spam.
如果将某个邮件标记为垃圾邮件 则最好是垃圾邮件
我们将介绍两种指标 精度和召回率
For this, we introduce use two metrics, precision and recall.
They will measure the exact things that we want namely,
它们将能够衡量我们想衡量的内容
the medical model needs to be a high-recall model,
即医疗模型需要是高召回率模型
and the email model needs to be a high-precision model.
电子邮件模型需要是高精度模型
We'll talk about them more in detail in the next couple of videos.
我们将在接下来的几个视频中详细讲解这两个概念